

srichetaruj@gmail.comsricheta92.github.io

**** +1(669)-278-3876 **?** San Jose, CA, USA

in sricheta-ruj ○ sricheta92

EDUCATION

SUMMARY AND OBJECTIVE

San Jose State Jan. 2018 to Dec. University 2019
Moster's in Software Engineering, GPA: 3.75/4.0

OCJP certified Experienced (4.5 years) Software Engineer in the field of Distributed Systems, cloud technologies, and application development with a strong foundation in Data Structures and Algorithms.

Nirma University Aug. 2009 to May 2013

Looking for summer internship opportunities.

Bachelors in Computer Science, GPA: 7.13/10

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Java, Javascript, Go

WEB TECHNOLOGIES: ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, KnockoutJS, BacknoneJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS/CSS, XML, Rest API/SOA, Ajax, HTML5

SQL/NOSQL DATABASE: MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, Solr, Riak

APPLICATION, TESTING & DATABASE FRAMEWORKS: gRPC, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Struts, JUnit, Spring Roo

DATA STREAMING FRAMEWORKS: Kafka, Spark, Flume, RabbitMQ

CLOUD: Heroku, Kong, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes

SCM AND VERSIONING TOOLS: Git, SVM, Perforce, JIRA, Maven, Ant, Gradle, Gulp

EMPLOYMENT

ASSOCIATED STUDENTS. SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY

Web Developer Student Intern - Part Time

San Jose, USA Mar. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Involved in maintenance and development of university website. (Adding new features, bug fixes, securing vulnerabilities of OWASP standards) in Java/JSP/Javascript
- Set up Oracle opensso enterprise on the iPlanet web server. Configured web agents for authentication of specific pages.

EDGEVERVE SYSTEMS

Member of Technical Staff

Pune, India Dec. 2016 to Dec. 2017

- Involved in revamping the UI of website of our Product, Rialto, changing the look and feel of various pages using jQuery, D3, and Bootstrap 4.
- Developed and peer tested Rest services in Spring Boot integrated with JPA and MySQL, thereby reducing the defect count to 30%.
- Developed new pages using Struts 2.0, JSP, JSTL and jQuery.

AMDOCS INC.

Software Developer

Pune, India Mar. 2015 to Nov. 2016

- Automated the code setup environment for new joiners, using ANT script that takes ~1 minute to setup env for coding, saving time up to 85%.
- Developed standalone widgets in MVVM (KnockoutJS) framework in TDD environment which helps the business user to build, manage, deploy the commercial website and coordinate between device.

CAPGEMINI INDIA PVT. LTD.

Software Engineer

Pune, India June 2013 to Mar. 2015

- Developed a Reconciliation Batch process which could read thousands of records from the database using SQL queries.
- Write into excel file using Apache POI in a defined format in minutes, thereby saving time up to 30%.
- Involved in development of screens using Java Swing and maintaining coding standards.

PROJECTS

Strands - Distributed File Store [gRPC Java, Netty, ProtoBuf, RAFT] (https://bit.ly/2TgctzR)

Sept. 2018 to Nov. 2018

- Developed fault tolerant, multi-cluster, circuit breaker pattern distributed data store using Netty and gRPC with ProtoBuf.
- Implemented RAFT consensus algorithm from scratch in gRPC Java.
- Developed in-memory data store with LRU cache-ability.
- Tested it with physical switches and Increased data delivery efficiency using bloom filters: murmur hash and memcache.

Multi-Tenant SaaS App - X, Y, Z axis scaling [MongoDB, Riak, K8s, AWS, Docker] (https://bit.ly/2HiNwCx)

Sept. 2018 to Nov. 2018

- Configured a 10 node Cluster using AWS EC2 instances in private subnet and multiple AZs to achieve high availability.
- Testing the Partition Tolerance of both MongoDB and Riak for the read & write and the effect of healing after partition.
- Deployed a Multi-Tenant Food Ordering App in Heroku & AWS with microservices scaling, sharding, load balancing, Kong API & Kubernetes.

Movie Ticket Portal [Kafka, MongoDB, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, ReactJS] (https://bit.ly/2LA09WM)

Mar. 2018 to Apr. 2018

- Developed Fandango like application for movie and movie hall booking. See the reviews and rating of the movie.
- Improved application response time by ~10% with the implementation of Cache using Redis and custom written connection pooling
- Created admin dashboard to display client activities, revenue, page visits, clicks, etc using ChartJS and MongoDB
- The application is tested for 10k concurrent connections in JMeter

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

JUNIT 5 FRAMEWORK. · Contributer